# MONIKA VALEJA

## PYTHON FULL STACK DEVELEOPER

- https://valejamonika.github.io/MY PORTFOLIO/
- ♥ Bhopal(MP)
- **\** 9039326737,8770212751
- in <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/monika-valejaba570020b/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/monika-valejaba570020b/</a>
- https://github.com/valejamonika

## Skills

## **Technical Skills**

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Bootstrap
- WordPress
- · Python-Django
- Django Rest Framework
- MySQL
- SQLite 3
- VB.Net
- C Language
- MS Office Package
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Pagemaker
- Tally Prime
- Marg

#### Tools

- PyCharm
- Python IDLE
- · Visual Studio Code
- MySQL Console
- Sublime Text 3
- Notepad ++
- WampServer
- Dev C++
- Postman

#### CARRIER OBJECTIVE

To gain technical and domain experience in a growth-oriented organization which will provide me opportunities for growth and ensure job satisfaction, while making a significant contribution to the success of the company as a Full stack Python Developer or Frontend Developer.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **PYTHON-DJANGO FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

## CNC Web World Technologies PVT LTD Duration - June 2021- Present

- To create plan and design of the webpages login, logout, forms using HTML, CSS and Bootstrap.
- Gathering information regarding frontend of the website social reach, location etc
- Developing Backend of Online Hospital Management System using SQLite 3.
- Using different icons for frontend of Online Hospital Management System using icons8.com

#### **COMPUTER TRAINER**

Sunny Institute, (Bhopal)

Duration - June 2018 - June 2021

- Train and instruct students of various schools, colleges and universities.
- Design and implement training schedules by creating batches according to course of enrolled students.
- Creating presentation and course material according to updated syllabus of Python, c, HTML, CSS, VB.Net, PGDCA. DCA etc.
- Train new technologies, software programs and applications like MS Office, Tally Prime, HTML, Adobe Photoshop etc.

## **PROJECTS**

## **SPORT CLUB MANAGEMENT &**

SCM is Admin and User both based which has Book Ground and Check Events module for users and Create and Manage Event and Check Booking's module for admin.

- <u>Tools Used PyCharm 2021</u>, Browser- Chrome.
- <u>Technologies</u> HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Python with Django, SQLite3.
- Registration, Login and Log Out functionality for users.
- Forget Password and OTP via Gmail Account functionality for users.
- Login and Log Out functionality for admin.
- Ground Booking by users.
- Add and Manage event, check bookings by admin.

## **Education**

- MCA RGPV (2020-2022)
- MCOM Barkatullah University (2017-2019)
- BCOM(CA)
   Barkatullah University
   (2014-2017)

#### **PROJECTS**

## DRF CRUD &

DRF Crud is created using Django Rest Framework

<u>Tools Used – Visual Studio Code, Browser- Chrome.</u>

<u>Technologies – Django Rest Framework</u>

 Add, Retrieve, Update, Delete Employee and their task using API View.

## CRUD PANEL &

CRUD Panel is based on CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) operation.

- Tools Used PyCharm 2021, Browser- Chrome
- Technologies HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Python with Django, SQLite3
- It has authentication for login and logout functionality.
- Insert new records in database .
- Update and Delete record. Display all records stored in database .

## YASISLAND 8

Yas Island is a project about shop, dine, stay and play like you mean it with insider guides and updates on enjoying very best of Yas Island experiences

- Tools Used Visual Studio Code, Browser- Chrome
- Technologies HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript.
- Responsive page contact us page having information to contact Yas Island.
- Send Us An Email Form is designed.
- Call Us and Find Us section is linked contact numbers and google map .